In this work, we tackle the problem of autonomous
long-term exploration for robots with fewer and
cheaper sensors compared to the state-of-the-art.
For visual sensing, our approach requires just an
RGB-D camera rather than expensive
LiDARs or a multitude of sensors.
All the exploration is computed in real-time
and on low-power computing hardware that
is cheaper compared to the existing
literature operating in similar settings.
The hardware consists of RB5—an
experimental wheeled-mobile robot
utilized to explore the environment for
long-term and on challenging terrains.
The robot has rocker-bogie suspensions, which allow
static rough-terrain adaptability without costly
computations for gait adaptation and planning.
It is built of metallic extrusions and acrylic
sheets, and the rocker and bogie linkages are
assembled from aluminum sheets and standoffs.
The exploration is based on a novel mixed
approach–a frontier- and sampling-based
method from the literature, which we extend
with a path-following vector field from the
aerial robotics domain, allowing the robot
to operate at lower update frequencies.
The detail of the algorithm and the exploration
path are shown in the third frame from the top
left, where the dome indicates the field of
view and the color the proximity to obstacles.
The robot uses the same actuation
strategy as that of a differential
drive vehicle to move straight and make turns
by controlling the left and right sets of
wheels in the same and opposite directions.
We conduct a set of field experiments in
autonomous long-term exploration in a variety
of environments, including indoors structured,
unstructured underground, and outdoors.
The approach further consists of a novel
methodology for human intervention,
when the robot is unable to move
with the local sensory information.
The methodology exploits LoRa–an inexpensive
long-range and low-power communication
technology from the internet-of-things
domain–and a custom communication protocol.
Here, a human operator guides the robot
via a smartphone that is connected
to a remotely located base station.